# KRISTA SIMMONS

•San Diego, CA 92104 •(805) 794-4737 •kristasimmons.design@gmail.com

• linkedin.com/in/krista-simmons • www.kristasimmons.io

## ABOUT ME

A front-end developer & ux/ui designer from Southern California. Passionate about learning new technologies, implementing and developing great user experience using JavaScript, HTML and CSS. Works well under time constraints and extremely self motivated. A very efficient Googler as well.

## SUMMARY OF SKILLS

## Technical:

- Primary Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Ruby, Ruby on Rails
- Knowledgeable: Git Version Control, SQL, PostgreSQL, Sass, RSpec

# Tools:

Atom, Github, Sketch, Wordpress, Balsamiq, Photoshop, InVision, MailChimp, Hootsuite

## Additional:

- Search Engine Optimization (SEO) & Google Analytics
- Wireframing & Prototyping
- **❖** Agile Methodologies
- Project Management
- User Experience

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### KSIMMONS DEVELOPMENT

March 2017- Current

Freelance Web Developer & Designer

San Diego, CA

- Designing and developing Shopify store for beverage accessory company
- Rapid prototyping of email templates and converted designs into HTML
- Creating custom Wordpress theme from Roots/Sage. Includes prototype design in Sketch, responsive layout and styling, adding site content and configuring plugins
- ❖ SEO implementation to existing Wordpress site
- iOS app design for nonprofit volunteer app

# SCIENTIST.COM

February 2017-March 2017

Full-Stack Web Development Intern

San Diego, CA

- Implementing a shipment/tracking API for both the customer and supplier portion of the web app
- Utilizing HTML, JavaScript, jQuery and Bootstrap for the front-end, and Ruby and CouchDB for the back-end
- Created web design wireframes/mockups using Sketch
- Responsible for testing the features and it's responsiveness across all browsers and devices

## SPECIALIST STAFFING SOLUTIONS

January 2015-October 2016

Technical Recruiter

San Diego, CA

- Involved in the full-cycle recruiting process for IT positions, from business development to sourcing candidates for open positions
- Extend, negotiate and close offers with both clients and candidates
- Write compelling job descriptions, interview guidelines, tailored and personalized Inmails
- Track, manage and analyze data through Salesforce CRM

## **KELLER WILLIAMS REALTY**

February 2014-August 2014

Social Media & Marketing Coordinator

San Diego, CA

- ❖ Prepared listing researches on the MLS databases for the Luxury Real Estate Division
- ❖ Managed and implemented social media accounts for 2 realtors, including Facebook, Twitter, Yelp, Google Plus and YouTube as well as creating a Wordpress blog
- Generated leads through phone prospecting and marketing tools such as Market Leader

# **EDUCATION**

LEARN ACADEMY

November 2016- February 2017

Full-Time immersive Web Development Boot camp

San Diego, CA

SAN DIEGO STATE UNIVERSITY

May 2015

College of Business Administration, Bachelor of Science, Marketing

San Diego, CA

# **INTERESTS**

- Blogging
- Event Planning

- Music Production
- User Experience